Finding Aid for George Steeh Papers 1946-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
George C. Steeh Papers 1946-2009 1960-1990
Steeh, George C., 1919-
1.75 linear ft.
Democratic state legislator from Macomb County, a member both of the House and the Senate, later appointed Macomb County District Court Judge. The collection includes biographical information, legislative files and reference materials, campaign files, constituent correspondence, and miscellaneous court opinions and orders.
9959 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The papers were donated by his son George C. Steeh, Jr. (donor no. 5445 in 1999; additional papers came from George C. Steeh, Sr. (donor no. 10621 in 2011.
The collection is open for research.
George C. Steeh grew up in Mount Clemens, Michigan, and received his A.B. degree in 1942 and his L.L.B. degree in 1949 from the University of Michigan. He married Barbara Leigh Young and had five children. Barbara's father was Professor Emeritus Leigh J. Young of the University of Michigan, and former Mayor of Ann Arbor. He joined the law firm of Neale and Hirt (later Neale and Steeh)--located in Mount Clemens--in 1950.
George C. Steeh was elected to the Michigan House of Representatives in 1954, the first Democrat ever to be elected from that Macomb County district. After serving one term, he was then elected to the State Senate for the Eleventh Senatorial District in 1956. He was reelected in 1958 and 1960, then he returned to the practice of law.
During his terms in the Senate, some of the issues the legislature considered included the institution of a state income tax, the revoking of the Veterans' Homestead Exemption Act, and the cigarette and alcohol nuisance tax. Steeh also served as a member of the State Board of Tax Appeals (1974-1980). In 1980 he was appointed Macomb County Circuit Court Judge, serving until 1990. Since then, Steeh served as visiting judge, arbitrator, facilitator, and member of Macomb case evaluation.
The George C. Steeh papers are divided into five series: Biographical / Personal; Legislative / Political Files; Constituent Correspondence; Other Activities and Macomb County Circuit Court.
Subjects:
Steeh, George C., 1919-; Macomb County (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Legislators--Michigan--Macomb County.; Michigan. Legislature. House of Representatives.; Michigan. Legislature. Senate.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Steeh, George C., 1919-; Macomb County (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Legislators--Michigan--Macomb County.
Genre/Form:
Photographs
- Biographical/Personal
  The Biographical/Personal series contains two biographical sketches, the letter he wrote to the Senate announcing his decision to not run for office in 1962, and some documents regarding his application to the judgeship in Macomb County. There is also a folder of clippings, and a folder of photographs containing four portraits of Steeh.
  - Biographical article from Bar Briefs, 2009 (Box 1)
  - 1955-1962 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1958-1960 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1961 and undated (Box 1)
  - U.S. Naval Service documents, 1946 (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan miscellaneous publications (Box 1)
  - Mount Clemens and Macomb County publications and other miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Legislative/Political Files
  Legislative/Political Files includes correspondence and other documents relating to his campaigns for office, and his associations with the Macomb County Democratic Committee. This series also contains the sub-series, Correspondence and Reference, which contains correspondence with other state officials and correspondence regarding constituent employment recommendations, as well as reports and copies of bills which Steeh used as reference for conducting legislative business.
  - Bills Introduced by Senator Steeh (includes voting records of 1957 and 1958 sessions), 1957-1962 (Box 1)
  - Campaign File, 1956-1960 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and Reference
    - 1959 (Box 1)
    - 1956-1963, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Macomb County Democratic Committee, 1962-1964 (Box 1)
- Constituent Correspondence
  The third series, Constituent Correspondence, is divided into General, Specific and Miscellaneous sub-series. The files in the Specific sub-series are arranged in alphabetical order by topic, and many have a Senate or House Bill number.
  - General
    - Education, 1958-1961 (Box 1)
    - Taxation, 1959-1961 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1962, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - By legislative topic
    - Accountancy Law (House Bill no.500), 1961 (Box 1)
    - Automobile Transport Truck Trailers (Senate Bill no.1189), 1961 (Box 1)
    - Great Lakes Submerged Lands Act (House Bill no.548), 1962 (Box 1)
    - Humane Slaughter (House Bill no.115), 1961-1962 (Box 1)
    - Mental Health Program, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
    - Milk Price Stabilizing (House Bill no.309), 1961 (Box 1)
    - Nuisance Tax, 1961 (Box 1)
    - School Bus Transportation Act, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Small Loan Limit Increase (House Bill no.289), 1961 (Box 1)
    - State Aid for Schools (House Bill no.243), 1962 (Box 1)
    - Sunday Closing (House Bill no.416), 1962 (Box 1)
    - Underground Gas Storage Facilities (Senate Bill no.1122), 1961 (Box 1)
    - Veterans' Homestead Exemption
      - Senate Bill no.1196, 1961 (Box 1)
      - Senate Bill no.1001, 1962 (Box 1)
- Other Activities
  The Other Activities series concerns Steeh's association with the Michigan State Board of Tax Appeals and the Michigan State Judicial Council. There is also a file for a murder case where Steeh was attorney for the defense.
  - Private practice case: Stanley Szyszlo murder case, 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - State Board of Tax Appeals, 1973-1980 (Box 2)
  - State Judicial Council, 1985-1986 (Box 2)
- Macomb County Circuit Court
  The Macomb County Circuit Court series consists of a selection made by Judge Steeh of those court orders and opinions that he considered of most significance.
  - Traci Ribitch case, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Orders and opinions (Box 2)